SAI BHASKER RAJU CHITTAPRAGADA

<u>schittap@uwo.ca</u> <u>|saibhaskerraju@outlook.com</u> |+1-(226)-998-4770 | Unit 60, 70 Chapman Court, London, ON, Canada http://saibhaskerraju.tk | https://www.linkedin.com/in/saibhaskerraju/ |https://github.com/uwobhaskerraju

Professional Summary:

Professional with over 3+ years of working experience involved in all phases of software development seeking to combine practical experience in a dynamic IT environment; with a strong background in software development, databases and Microsoft's Technology Stack.

Education:

Master of Engineering - Software Engineering

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020

The University of Western Ontario, London, ON, CA

Concentration: Full Stack Web Development (Angular 8, Node.js, MongoDB) and Data Analytics

MEng Project: Empire Hut is a web application built to buy/sell property in a secured and decentralized way. It leverages the power of Ethereum blockchain to make it secure and tamper proof. This application tracks your assets and transactions, allows users to buy/sell property in minutes by eliminating paperwork, middlemen and costs, for a small transaction fee.

Professional Experience:

Yuser Inc - London, Canada May 2020 - Present

Full Stack Developer

Revamped the application to use Neo4j graph databases instead of MongoDB, bringing down query time from seconds to milliseconds

Environment: Neo4i, Cypher, JavaScript, React, Feathers.JS

Cognizant Technology Solutions - Hyderabad, India

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019

Programmer Analyst

Developed REST APIs for "TheFA - Matchday" using C# and deployed to Azure API Management Portal for end users to consume without any latency.

- Developed APIs to show LIVE status of matches to keep users posted
- Developed APIs to display payment dues of players for signed up matches
- Worked on security improvements of authorization and authentication REST APIs
- Implemented design patterns to maintain code re-usability and maintainability

Environment: C#.NET, Azure Logic Apps and Azure API Management

Prolifics Corporation - Hyderabad, India

July 2016 - Oct 2018

Associate Software Engineer

Created SSIS Packages for Hudson Advisors for their daily ETL Operations, efficiently loaded high volume data per day and gracefully handled errors to manage failures.

- Revamped the existing logic to import huge unstructured excel sheet data into database using C# and Spreadsheet Gear to streamline overall data loading process and error logging
- Earned " RACE " award twice for outstanding performance in data migration project from on-premise to Azure
- Accelerated the data loading process by using In-Memory Tables as stage tables in SQL Server
- Reduced deployment time to 5 minutes from 20min by automating the continuous integration process using PowerShell scripts

Environment: C#.NET, Azure Logic Apps, Azure SQL Datawarehouse, PowerShell, SSIS, SQL Server, S3 Bucket and Amazon Redshift

Voluntary Experience:

Microsoft Student Partner

Jan 2020 - Dec 2020 | March 2015 - April 2016

Student Trainer and Campus Ambassador

Delivered hands-on training sessions in my college to enable students on fundamentals of Azure. These activities were part of Azure Learning to empower students on latest technologies which includes MS Bot Framework.

Certifications: